Alexander Vellios

New York, NY 10570

Phone: 914 584 8351 | Email: av@agavepv.com

 $Github: \underline{https://github.com/TheGreekCuban} \mid LinkedIn: \underline{https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexander-vellios/linkedIn.} \mid \underline{https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexander-vellios/linkedIn.} \mid \underline{https://github.com/TheGreekCuban} \mid \underline{https://github.com/In/alexander-vellios/linkedIn.} \mid \underline{https://git$

Portfolio: https://vellios-professional-portfolio.herokuapp.com/home.html

Personal Overview

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in commercial real estate. Over one year of experience with a focus on the MERN stack. Strong skills in communication, management, organization, team building, and networking. Fluent in Greek and Spanish.

Education

Web Development Bootcamp Certificate Bachelors of Science Hotel Restaurant & Institutional Management

Columbia University 2019 University Of Delaware 2014

New York, New York Newark, DE

Technical Skills

Front End: HTML5 | CSS3 | Javascript | JQuery | Bootstrap | Materialize | Handlebars.js | React.js

Back End: Node.js | MySQL | MongoDB | Express.js | Sequelize.js | Firebase

Projects

Butterfly

- Educational/Institutional social messaging application intended to be a combination of Slack and Canvas. Allows teachers/managers to both communicate in an open forum and manage their students/employees in one application.
- Main contributor on a team of four developers
- **Duties:** Focused on creating the models for the user, streams and messages. Constructed both the backend routes and the frontend code that deals with retrieving and displaying all the information related to the user's streams and messages in that stream.
- **Technologies:** mongoDB, Mongoose.js, React.js, Passport.js, Express,js, Node.js, Handlebars.js, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS
- **Github:** https://github.com/AllenDCooper/Butterfly
- **Deployed Link:** https://social-butterfly-app.herokuapp.com/

Renegade Trailbrew App

- Gives user the five closest local breweries and top five hiking trails in the area based on your location.
- Main contributor on a team of four developers
- **Duties:** Focused on building the front end using materialize, css and jquery. Created all the functionality with relation to the storing and manipulation of data on a firebase database.
- **Technologies:** Google Maps API, Hiking Project API, and the Open Brewery API, Materialize, HTML, CSS, Firebase, JQuery
- **Github:** https://github.com/bleauwonder/renegades-of-silicon-alley
- Deployed Link: https://bleauwonder.github.io/renegades-of-silicon-alley/

WeardrobeDB

- A full stack closet organizer and outfit generator application
- Lead and managed a team of four developers in addition to being a main contributor
- App has the ability to randomize an outfit using the user's wardrobe. Users can track their statistics to see what their most worn article, least worn article, style breakdown and seasonality breakdowns are.
- **Duties:** Focused on creating all the functionality to store the data using a custom ORM and sequelize.js, pulling and manipulating the data from the backend in order to implement it in the appropriate format using chart.js
- Technologies: MySQL, Sequelize.js, Passport.js, Express.js, Node.js, Handlebars.js, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS
- **Github:** https://github.com/anahisbarrie/weardrobeDB
- Deployed Link: https://shrouded-brushlands-82538.herokuapp.com/

ScrapeOholic

- Full stack web application scrapes articles off TheRealDeal.com and displays the articles with relevant information on the web application.
- Client has the option to add an article to their saved collection. Once saved, the user can add notes to articles of importance.
- Duties: Focused on constructing both the front and the back end strictly adhering to the MVC format.
- **Technologies:** Heroku was used for deployment, mongoDB and Mongoose.js were used to store and manipulate the data. In addition Node.js, Express.js, Handlebars.js, CSS, HTML, jQuery
- **Github:** https://github.com/TheGreekCuban/scrape-oholic
- **Deployed Link:** https://scrape-oholic.herokuapp.com/

Professional Experience

Lead Web Developer at Agave Property Ventures: Newark, NJ August 2019 - Present

- Migrated the Agave Property Ventures website from SquareSpace to the company server
- Reconstructed the site using the MERN stack
- Added a real estate news scraper that allows users to stay current with the local real estate news from a few major publications
- Plans to create a mobile application using React Native by Summer 2020

Co-Founder at Agave Property Ventures: Newark, NJ June 2018 – Present

- Syndicated \$80,000 for the acquisition of Agave Property Ventures' first property
- Negotiated the acquisition of 42 3rd Street to a purchase price that created \$40,000 in equity upon closing
- Cultivated relationships with Newark Department Of Buildings and Housing Authority
- Successfully renovated the property and fully leased both units in under 8 weeks

Associate Director at Compass with The Abrams Retail Strategies: Manhattan, NY August 2017 – February 2019

- Represented the landlord of 168 Fifth Avenue, NY, NY to negotiate the lease of ZOLA, an e-commerce wedding registry business, for their first retail location.
- Represented Thomas Moser, a luxury furniture store, in the sublease of their retail space located at 1015 Madison Avenue, NY, NY. Subleased the space to Christopher Martin Art Gallery. The Abrams Retail Strategies Team. represented both sides of this deal.
- Represented the landlord of 900 Madison Avenue, NY, NY to negotiate the lease of the retail space to Zimmerman, a luxury Australian fashion brand.
- Successfully leased and subleased over 10,000 square feet of NYC prime retail space in just under two years.

Honors & Volunteer Work

Honored by the New York Times in The January 2017 edition as one of New York City's Dealmakers of 2016. The award was for the placement of TNH Development into their new office space at 45 Rockefeller Plaza.

Volunteered with Big Brother Big Sisters' Family Services Of Westchester Division starting in late 2018. Currently a mentor to a 13-year-old young adult with a focus on academics and sports.